CURRICULUM

Carlos Enrique Brito Rodríguez

Bachelor's Degree: Accounting Email: cbrito1994@gmail.com Phone: 0445537041295

Github: https://github.com/cbrito1994

Linkedin: https://www.linkedin.com/in/carlos-brito-50a481b4/

Professional and life objective:

Create new ways and innovative solutions to people's everyday problems with the use of cuttingedge technology. Surround myself with different people from various areas of expertise and collaborate together to resolve today issues and create a positive and helpful impact on society.

ACADEMIC BACKGROUND:

2017-2018 Post-Bachellor Degree in Corporate Finance

Universidad Panamericana, Mexico City

2013-2017 Bachelor's Degree in Accounting

Universidad Panamericana, Mexico City

2000-2012 Primary, High School

Liceo Mexicano Japones, A.C.

WORKING EXPERIENCE:

2016-2018 Tax Analyst

Grupo Farmacos Especializados

Mexican pharmaceutical retailer company specialist on the selling of medicine and medical equipment to government and private entities.

I worked as a tax analyst, having as primarily activities:

- Monthly and annually tax calculations.
- Legal tax planning to help the company reduce its tax payments.
- Record of the dividends and capital reductions given to the shareholders.
- Incorporation of new companies.
- Revision of related parties' contracts and transfer pricing studies.
- Participate on the planning of corporate restructures.

Revision of Tax Reports.

Major accomplishments:

- Being involved in the mergers of various of the group's companies.
- Being involved in the tax planning for distribution of dividends to the shareholders.

March2019-present Innovation and Technology Leader

BHR Mexico

Ninth biggest accountants, lawyers and consultants' firm in Mexico. Having clients from any kind of industry including worldwide known companies such as Samsonite, Universal Pictures and others from countries like China, India, USA and Japan.

My main activities are:

- Be in charge of the Innovation and Technology Department which focuses on the development of systems to sell and self-implement for the firm.
- Planning of new technological systems focused on the needs of companies and for the firm self-implementation.
- Keep in touch with possible customers to arrange meetings in order to negotiate and sell the firm's wide range of services.

Major accomplishments:

- Planning of a tax calculation system that started selling in 2020.
- Planning of a Human Resources system which will help on the better management of the worker's data and reduction of the time consumption from the Human Resources Department tasks.
- Development of the 2019's Innovation and Technology Contest from where 1 major technological project came up that will have the effects of cutting expenses, reducing the time consumption on administrative tasks and improving the accuracy of the accounting reports.
- Being involved with partners and managers in the negotiation on the selling of the firm's services.
- In 2020, after 1 year of good work and accomplishments, the Managing Partner of the firm gave me task of managing the newly developed Training Department in which, with the help of 2 other employees, we came up with a 1-year training plan for the 100 employees in Mexico City and that have had great results according to the feedback

CODING KNOWLEDGE & EXPERIENCE

Frontend:

- HTML
- CSS
- Javascript

Backend:

NodeJs

Major Projects:

- COVID Tracker:
 - Website that allows you to know the latest news of COVID 19 around the world and in specific countries.
 - Built with HTML, Foundation (CSS Framework), Javascript, CNN News and Disease.sh APIs.
 - Website Link: https://gutihi85.github.io/covid tracker/
- Password Generator:
 - Web app that allows you to create a totally random password based on certain inputs.
 - o Built with HTML, CSS and Javascript.
 - o Website Link: https://cbrito1994.github.io/H3-Password-Generator/
- Hockey Quiz:
 - Web quiz that measures your knowledge in hockey.
 - o Built with HTML, CSS and Javascript.
 - o Website Link: https://cbrito1994.github.io/P4-Hockey-Quiz/index.html

PERSONAL AND PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

Skills:

- Results oriented
- Leadership
- Committed
- Self-driven
- Confident
- Teammate

Languages:

Certificate in Advance English, from Cambridge University

• Basic Japanese

Software uses:

- Visual Studio Code
- Office (Word, Excel, Power Point)

COMPLEMENTARY INFORMATION

- Studied at Sendagaya Japanese Language Institue in Tokyo, Japan. July 2012- December 2012
- Studied at Language Studies International in Vancouver, Canada. January 2013- June 2013

EXTRACURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

- Ice hockey player.
- Going to the gym.